Guide to the Algernon David Black Papers
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
Algernon David Black Papers,
[ca. 1932]-1979.
Black, Algernon D. (Algernon David), 1900-1993.
12 linear ft (ca. 14,035 items in 27 boxes).
Columbia University. Rare Book and Manuscript Library, New York, NY.
4079285
Biographical Note
Writer, lecturer, and leader of the New York Society for Ethical Culture. A.D. Black died in 1993.
Scope and Content
Correspondence, speeches, memoranda, minutes, and publications, including radio talks and platform addresses given at the Society, the papers of several housing committees on which Black served, and autobiographical subject files compiled by Black and documenting his participation in many organizations and social causes.
Arrangement
Selected materials cataloged; remainder arranged.
Subjects
Society for Ethical Culture.; United States--Social conditions.; Radio programs.; Housing.; Ethics--Societies, etc.; Liberalism.; Lectures.; Minutes.; Authors.
Acquisition
M74 Black, Algernon D.
Gift of Algernon D. Black, 1974, 1976, 1979 & 1981.
Restrictions on Access
This collection is located off-site. You will need to request this material at least twenty-four (24) hours in advance to use the collection in the Rare Book and Manuscript Library reading room.
- Series I: Catalogued correspondence
  - Cherne, Leo
  - Cousins, Norman
  - Fosdick, Harry Emerson
  - Ickes, Harold L.
  - Isaacs, Stanley M.
  - La Farge, Oliver
  - Parker, Dorothy
  - Pike, James A.
  - Radhakrishaan, Sarvepalli, 1888-
  - Roosevelt, Eleanor
  - Roosevelt, Nicholas
  - Sanger, Margaret
  - Solow, Herbert
  - Stokowski, Leopold
  - Swope, Herbert Bayard
  - Thomas, Norman
  - White, Walter
  - Platform Addresses (Box 1-3)
  - Radio Talks (Box 4-5)
  - Publications (Box 6)
  - City-Wide Citizens Committee on Harlem, 1941-1947 (Box 7-8)
  - New York State Committee Against Discrimination in Housing, 1948-1963 (Box 9-11)
  - National Committee Against Discrimination in Housing, 1949 -1967 (Box 12-14)
  - Financial records of New York and National Committees (Box 14)
  - Appendix to Committee records (Box 15)
  - Records of three parallel organizations while the NYSCDH and NCDH were in effect, 1949-1963 (Box 16)
  - Subject File. See attached Folder list (Box 17-27)
- Series II: Algernon D. Black --Platform Addresses, 1932 -1973
  - Given at regular Sunday morning meetings of the New York Society for Ethical Culture (Box 17-27)
  - 1932 January 17: The Myth of Rugged Individualism (Box 1-3)
  - 1933 November 6: Our Political Ideals and the City Election (Box 1-3)
  - 1934
    - January 28: The Rights of Children (Box 1-3)
    - April 15: The Coming Struggle for Power (Box 1-3)
    - November 11: How Can We Prepare for Peace? (Box 1-3)
  - 1935
    - April (Easter): New Horizons (Box 1-3)
    - November 24: "It Can't Happen Here" -- Sinclair Lewis (Box 1-3)
  - 1936
    - (No date): Mr. Justice Brandeis (Box 1-3)
    - (No date): Ethical Values in Crisis: The Spanish Revolt (Box 1-3)
    - March 1: Betrayal in Politics (Box 1-3)
  - 1937
    - (No date): The Problem of Divorce (Box 1-3)
    - (No date): The Meaning of Industrial Unrest (Box 1-3)
    - (Easter): Death and Birth of a World (Box 1-3)
    - October 24: Can Democracy Defeat Dictatorship? (Box 1-3)
    - November 14: Should the Church Fight Radicalism? (Box 1-3)
  - 1938
    - January 23: What Kind of Revolution Does American Youth Want? (Box 1-3)
    - February 27: The War Spirit Versus the People's Will to Peace (Box 1-3)
    - March 27: American Patriotism --What Does It Mean? (Box 1-3)
    - October 30: Democracy: The Road Ahead (Box 1-3)
    - November 20: Anti-Semitism: What Is the Answer? (Box 1-3)
  - 1939
    - January 15: "Man's Hope" and "Man's Fate": Andre Malraux (Box 1-3)
    - February 7: The Choice Before American Youth Today (Box 1-3)
    - April 9: Human Faith Under Fire (Box 1-3)
    - September 10: Does Modern Man Need Religion? (Box 1-3)
    - November 12: The Meaning of Hitler (Box 1-3)
    - November 19: The Hard Road to Peace (Box 1-3)
  - 1940
    - January 14: Integrity in Public Life (Box 1-3)
    - February 18: Is the New Deal Dead? (Box 1-3)
    - March 24: A New World: Man's Unconquerable Hope (Box 1-3)
    - October 20: The Rediscovery of Citizenship (Box 1-3)
    - November 10: Is Pacifism the Answer? (Armistice Day) (Box 1-3)
  - 1941
    - February 2: Have Men Lost Their God? (Box 1-3)
    - February 9: The Individual and Mass Behavior (Box 1-3)
    - March 9: Youth's Call to the Older Generation (Box 1-3)
    - April 13: The Ethics of Jesus in a World at War (Box 1-3)
    - June 8: Youth in Search of Religion (Box 1-3)
    - October 5: Dare We Believe in People? (Box 1-3)
    - October 26: Can We Defeat Fascism? (Box 1-3)
    - November 16: American Attitude Toward Soviet Russia (Box 1-3)
    - December 21: Where Men Meet to Seek --A Christmas Talk (Box 1-3)
  - 1942
    - January 18: The War Crisis and This Generation (Box 1-3)
    - March 29: A World Without Hitler (Box 1-3)
    - May 10: Democracy’s Unfinished Business (Box 1-3)
    - October 25: Does the World Want Peace? (Box 1-3)
  - 1943
    - March 7: A World Without Hate (Box 1-3)
    - March 14: Our Godless Age (Box 1-3)
    - March 21: The Challenge of Soviet Russia (Box 1-3)
    - March 28: Henry Wallace and the Prophetic Vision (Box 1-3)
    - May 18: Japanese-Americans: Fellow Citizens (Box 1-3)
    - June 13: America's Inner Crisis (Box 1-3)
    - October 31: The Reconstruction of Democratic Society: What Is America's Religion? (Box 1-3)
    - November 7: The Reconstruction of Democratic Society: (Box 1-3)
    - November 7: Free Enterprise Versus Collectivism (Box 1-3)
    - November 14: The Reconstruction of Democratic Society: Will Victory Bring Peace? (Box 1-3)
    - November 21: The Reconstruction of Democratic Society: Wanted: A New Citizenship (Box 1-3)
  - 1944
    - April 16: America's Hour of Danger: Your Stake in the Coming Peace (Box 1-3)
    - April 23: The Rising Tide of Race Conflict (Box 1-3)
    - July 23: Spiritual Security in Wartime (Box 1-3)
    - October 1: The Meaning of Hitler's Defeat (Box 1-3)
    - October 8: The Return of the Soldier (Box 1-3)
    - October 15: The World Crisis and Its Meaning: Is Peace an Illusion? (Box 1-3)
    - October 22 The World Crisis and Its Meaning: What Are We Living For? (Box 1-3)
  - 1945
    - April 1: The Reconstruction of Democratic Faith: The Rebirth of the Democratic World -- An Easter Address (Box 1-3)
    - April 8: The Reconstruction of Democratic Faith: Soviet Russia --A Promise or a Threat? (Box 1-3)
    - April 15: The Reconstruction of Democratic Faith" The Ethics of Private Property Re-Examined (Box 1-3)
    - April 22: Victory: A Challenge to the Schools of America (Box 1-3)
    - June 10: Religion in the Post-War Period (Box 1-3)
    - October 28: A Faith for Free Americans: I: Have We Destroyed Fascism? (Box 1-3)
    - November 4: A Faith for Free Americans: II: Will Collectivism End Freedom? (Box 1-3)
    - November 11: A Faith for Free Americans: III: War or Peace: Science Forces the Issue (Box 1-3)
    - November 18: A Faith for Free Americans: IV: In War and Peace (Box 1-3)
  - 1946
    - February 24: Is Anti-Semitism a Christian Problem (Box 1-3)
    - March 3: The Role of Youth in the Post-War World (Box 1-3)
    - October 27: Must Capitalism Fight Socialism? (Box 1-3)
    - November 3: The Corruption of Democracy (Box 1-3)
    - November 10: The Individual and the Drift to War (Box 1-3)
    - November 17: Religion at the Crossroads (Box 1-3)
  - 1947
    - February 23: On Being an American (Box 1-3)
    - March 2: An Ethical Challenge to Businessmen (Box 1-3)
    - March 9: The Twilight of Imperialism (Box 1-3)
    - March 16: The Sources of Our Faith in People (Box 1-3)
    - October 26: A Faith in God Re-Examined (Box 1-3)
    - November 2: A Faith in Man Re-Examined (Box 1-3)
    - November 9: The Will to Peace: An Armistice Day Address (Box 1-3)
  - 1948
    - February 29: What Is Loyalty? (Box 1-3)
    - March 7: A Man's Religion and His Politics (Box 1-3)
    - March 14: Wanted: An Honest Morality (Box 1-3)
    - April 25: War or Peace With Russia? (Box 1-3)
    - November 28: Has Science Destroyed Faith? (Box 1-3)
    - December 5: Wanted: A New Political Ethics (Box 1-3)
    - December 12: Work Incentives in a New Social Order (Box 1-3)
  - 1949
    - April 10: Moses: His God and His Ethics (Box 1-3)
    - April 17: Jesus: His God and His Ethics (Box 1-3)
    - April 24: The Fear of Communism and Democratic Faith (Box 1-3)
    - May1: Reconstructing International Relations (Box 1-3)
    - September 25: The Meaning of Man’s Quest for God (Box 1-3)
    - October 2: The Conflict of Church and Sate (Box 1-3)
    - October 9: Communism and the World Crisis (Box 1-3)
    - October 16: Can We Still Believe in People? (Box 1-3)
  - 1950
    - April 16: A Dying Imperialism and the Birth of a New World (Box 1-3)
    - November 12: The World Crisis and Its Meaning (Box 1-3)
    - November 19: The Welfare State: Its Strengths and Weaknesses (Box 1-3)
    - November 26: Who Are the Loyal Americans? (Box 1-3)
  - 1951
    - April 1: America's -Hour of Danger (Box 1-3)
    - April 29: America's Sense of Values (Box 1-3)
    - May Ethical Platform (5 addresses) (Box 1-3)
    - October 7: The Individual Under Socialism (Box 1-3)
    - October 14: The Reformation of Democracy (Box 1-3)
    - October-November: Ethical Platform (5 addresses) (Box 1-3)
  - 1952
    - January: Ethical Platform (1 ADB address) (Box 1-3)
    - February 17: Honor in Public Life (Box 1-3)
    - February 24: Essentials of an Ethical Economy (Box 1-3)
    - March 2: The Moral Basis for Peace With Russia (Box 1-3)
    - September 31: Are We Fit for Freedom? (Box 1-3)
    - November 9: America's Decision: What Does It Mean? (Box 1-3)
    - November 16: The Fascist Threat to American Freedom (Box 1-3)
    - Ethical Platform: Digests of: l) America’s Decision: What Does It Mean? (11/9); 2)The Fascist Threat to America's Freedom (11/16); 3)Can Men Live Without God? (11/23); and addresses by J. Nathanson. (Box 1-3)
    - December 7: War or Peace - Do We Have a Choice? (Box 1-3)
  - 1953
    - April 12: A World Without Stalin (Box 1-3)
    - April 19: The Honor of a Citizen (Box 1-3)
    - March-April: Ethical Platform (4 ADB addresses) (Box 1-3)
    - September 20: Our Quest for Security (Box 1-3)
    - October 4: Capitalism, Socialism and Human Welfare (Box 1-3)
    - October 25: Democratic Versus Authoritarian Religion (Box 1-3)
  - (1954 No Platform Addresses) (Box 1-3)
  - 1955
    - March 27: Capitalism, Socialism and Human Welfare (Box 1-3)
    - April 3: Israel and the World's Conscience (Box 1-3)
    - April 10: Resurrection of the Human Spirit (Box 1-3)
    - April 17: Loyalty in a Revolutionary Age (Box 1-3)
    - April 24: India: Spiritual Challenge to the West (Box 1-3)
    - April-May: Ethical Platform: Digests of: l)Israel and the World's Conscience (4/3); 2) The Resurrection of the Human Spirit -An Easter address (4/10); 3)Loyalty in a Revolutionary Age (4/17); 4)India: Spiritual Challenge to the West (4/24); and an address by J. Nathanson. (Box 1-3)
    - November 13: War Begins in the Minds of Men (Box 1-3)
    - November 20: Can We Depend Upon Human Reason? (Box 1-3)
  - 1956
    - March 4: Ethical Faith in a Godless World (Box 1-3)
    - March 18: Racial Segregation: America's Dilemma (Box 1-3)
    - July 8: Is There a Law of Righteousness? (Box 1-3)
    - November 11: The World Crisis -America's Responsibility (Box 1-3)
    - October-November: Ethical Platform: Digests of: l) Man in Search of God (10/28); 2)The Redemption of Democracy (11/4); 3) The World Crisis: Our American Responsibilities (11/11); 4) Our Happiness and Our Moral Values (11/18); and an address by H. Neumann. (Box 1-3)
  - 1957
    - March 24: The Israel-Arab Conflict and the Conscience of the World (Box 1-3)
    - April 14: Race Conflict-America's Dilemma (Box 1-3)
    - April 21: Spiritual Values and the Pursuit of Happiness (Box 1-3)
    - Ethical Platform: Digests of: l)Parents, Children, and the American Family (4/7); 2)Race Conflict -America's Dilemma (4/14); 3)Spiritual Values and the Pursuit of Happiness (4/21); and an address by H. Neumann. (Box 1-3)
    - July 14: Atomic Energy for Life or Death (Box 1-3)
    - December 8: Juvenile Crime: Whose Responsibility? (Box 1-3)
    - December 15: Soviet Achievement -Its Implications for America (Box 1-3)
    - Ethical Platform (3 ABD addresses) (Box 1-3)
  - 1958
    - March 16: The Ordeal of American Youth (Box 1-3)
    - March 23: Wanted: An Ethical Foreign Policy (Box 1-3)
    - March 30: American Labor Under Fire (Box 1-3)
    - July 6: Foundations of American Independence: Religious Freedom (Box 1-3)
    - July 13: Foundations of American Independence: Human Rights (Box 1-3)
    - October 12: Little Rock: Symbol of America's Dilemma (Box 1-3)
    - October 19: How Can Religion Help Children Face Life? (Box 1-3)
    - October Our Relations With China -The Ethical Question (Box 1-3)
    - November 1: Can Humanism Meet Man’s Spiritual Need? (Box 1-3)
  - 1959
    - February 15: Organ Dedication and Meetinghouse Rededication (With J. Nathanson) March 1: The Affluent Society -An Ethical View (Box 1-3)
    - March 8: Our Faith in Human Equality (Box 1-3)
    - March 15: Love and Hate in Human Relations (Box 1-3)
    - March 22: Ancient Prophecy and the Space Age (Box 1-3)
    - July 26: The Meaning of Ethical Culture (Box 1-3)
    - November 22: American-Soviet Relations: The Individual's Responsibility (Box 1-3)
    - November 29: Youth's Challenge to the Older Generation (Box 1-3)
    - December 6: The Family of Man: Our Common Ground of Faith (Box 1-3)
    - December 13: The Courage to Live (Box 1-3)
  - 1960
    - April 3: The Plight of the City --Citizens and Politicians (Box 1-3)
    - April 10: Our Image of America (Box 1-3)
    - April 17: The Moral Crisis of Our Time --An Easter Address (Box 1-3)
    - April 24: Disarmament and the Hope for a Lasting Peace (Box 1-3)
    - July 24: What Is the Greatest Challenge to Education (Box 1-3)
    - July 31: Peace Is Everyone's Responsibility (Box 1-3)
    - October 9: An Ethical View of Intermarriage (Box 1-3)
    - October 16: What We Have Learned About Human Nature in the (Box 1-3)
    - 20th Century (Box 1-3)
    - October 23: The Reconstruction of American Ideals (Box 1-3)
    - October 30: Ethical Issues of the Election (Box 1-3)
    - November 6: Wanted: A Foreign Policy for Peace (Box 1-3)
  - 1961
    - February 19: Our Sources of Inner Strength (Box 1-3)
    - February 26: American Youth, Its Rights and Responsibilities (Box 1-3)
    - March 5: The Quest for World Community - Dream or Reality? (Box 1-3)
    - March 12: Landlords and Tenants: The Ethics of Property (Box 1-3)
    - March 19: The Faith in God Re-Examined (Box 1-3)
    - May 28: Ethical Humanism in the Changing World (Box 1-3)
    - November 5: The Election, the City and the Citizen (Box 1-3)
    - November 12: Reflections on Life and Death in the Nuclear Age (Box 1-3)
    - November 19: The Ten Commandments and Our Changing Morality (Box 1-3)
    - December 3: Our Attitude Toward the Communist World (Box 1-3)
    - December 10: What We Stand For -- The Meaning of Ethical Faith (Box 1-3)
  - 1962
    - March 25: An Ethical Critique of "Slums and Suburbs" by (Box 1-3)
    - Dr. James B. Conant (Box 1-3)
    - April 1: War and the Human Conscience (Box 1-3)
    - April 8: The Older Generation — Has It a Place in Modern (Box 1-3)
    - Civilization? (Box 1-3)
    - April 15: The Culture of Poverty and the Cult of Revolution (Box 1-3)
    - April 22: The Meaning of Death and Resurrection -~ An Easter Address (Box 1-3)
    - September 9: Our Religious Freedom and the Supreme Court (Box 1-3)
    - September 16: Has Science Destroyed Our Faith? (Box 1-3)
    - September 23: What Is a Good Life? (Box 1-3)
    - September 30: The American Dream Our Unfinished Business (Box 1-3)
    - October 7:One World or None (Box 1-3)
  - 1963
    - February 10: Lincoln and the Emancipation Proclamation -A Century Later (Box 1-3)
    - February 17: Myth and Reality: What Can a Man Believe? (Box 1-3)
    - February 24: American Labor Faces a New Challenge (Box 1-3)
    - March 3: Terminating Life: Has Man the Right to Make This Decision? (Ethical Aspects of Euthanasia) (Box 1-3)
    - March 10: Cuba and the Foundations of Peace (Box 1-3)
    - June 16: Our Freedom at Stake --National Unity and States' Rights (Box 1-3)
    - November 17: Civil Disobedience and Loyalty --Are They Contradictory? (Box 1-3)
    - November 24: The Death of the President Birth Control --Personal Ethics and Public Policy (Box 1-3)
    - December: Ethical Platform (2 ADB addresses) (Box 1-3)
  - 1964
    - March 22: Human Destiny and Human Happiness (Box 1-3)
    - March 29: The Power to Create and the Power to Love (Box 1-3)
    - June 28: The American Promise: What Is Required of Us? (Box 1-3)
    - August 23: Men -Angels, Devils or Humans? (revised 7/10/66) (Box 1-3)
    - September 20: What Are the Loyalties of American Youth? (Box 1-3)
    - September 27: Integrity in Public Life (Box 1-3)
    - October 4: The War Nobody Wants (Box 1-3)
    - October 11: Free Enterprise, Poverty and Planning (Box 1-3)
    - October 18: Our Sons and Our Daughters (Box 1-3)
    - December 13: And the Walls Came Tumbling Down (Box 1-3)
  - 1965
    - January 31: Our Attitude Toward China (Box 1-3)
    - February 7: Increasing Crime: The Danger in Our City (Box 1-3)
    - February 14: Lincoln: The Promises Men Live By (Box 1-3)
    - February 21: Do We Still Fear Intermarriage? (Box 1-3)
    - February 28: The Perils of Humanism (Box 1-3)
    - June 27: Peace Is Everyone's Responsibility (Box 1-3)
    - October 31: Crucial Issues in the City Elections (Box 1-3)
    - November 7: The Anti-Poverty Program: Hand-Out or Social Reconstruction? (Box 1-3)
    - November 14: The War in Vietnam and America's Conscience (Box 1-3)
    - December 19: Planets, People and Promises --A Holiday Message for Young and Old (Box 1-3)
  - 1966
    - March 6: Marriage and Divorce: Light and Shadow in Family Life (Box 1-3)
    - March 13: Ghettos in the Promised L~nd (Box 1-3)
    - March 20: The Double Standard in International Morality (Box 1-3)
    - March 27: In Defense of Humanism (Box 1-3)
    - May 15: Three Tributes to the Ethical Movement on Its 90th Anniversary, and Ethical Faith in a Revolutionary Age (Box 1-3)
    - July 10: Men --Angels, Devils or Humans? (revised version see also 8/23/64.) (Box 1-3)
    - November 27: The Wretched of the Earth (Box 1-3)
    - December 4: Liberalism and the New Left (Box 1-3)
    - December 11: The Victories of War and the Defeats of Peace (Box 1-3)
    - December 18: The Happiness We Seek and the Happiness We Find (Box 1-3)
    - December 25: A Christmas Message (Box 1-3)
  - 1967
    - March 12: The Abortion Issue and the Sanctity of Life (Box 1-3)
    - March 19: The Growing Conservative Movement: Challenge to America's Freedom (Box 1-3)
    - March 26: You Shall Be As Gods (Box 1-3)
    - July 9: Does Might Make Right? (Box 1-3)
    - July 30: Human Values in American Culture (A Conversation Between A.D. Black and James Farmer) (Box 1-3)
    - November 26: A World Worth Fighting For (Box 1-3)
    - December 3: Myth and Reality: Our Gods and Our Heroes (Box 1-3)
    - December 10: Racism Is a Two-Way Street (Box 1-3)
  - 1968
    - February 11: The Strength and the Might of the Powerless (Box 1-3)
    - March 3: Ideals and Illusions in World Affairs (Box 1-3)
    - March 24: The Child's Future and the World’s Uncertainty (Box 1-3)
    - March 31: The Keys to the City (Box 1-3)
    - April 7: Black and White Americans: A Tribute to Dr. Martin Luther King, Jr. (Box 1-3)
    - May 19: The Education of the Child in Ethical Humanism (Box 1-3)
    - June 9: The Heroic in Life --A Tribute to Robert Kennedy (Box 1-3)
    - July 14: Housing Issues in the Present Urban Crisis (Box 1-3)
  - 1969
    - March 30: Can American Civilization Save Itself? (Box 1-3)
    - June 8: Politics and Ethics: Our Fears and Hopes for the City (Box 1-3)
    - June 13: Youth's Revolt: Promises and Compromises (Box 1-3)
    - August 10: How We See Ourselves (Box 1-3)
    - November 23: The Caves We Live In (Box 1-3)
    - November 30: The Forgotten American (Box 1-3)
    - December 7: A World Without God (Box 1-3)
    - December 21: The Peacemakers (Box 1-3)
  - 1970
    - March 29: Non-Violence and Violence in Religion --An Easter Address (Box 1-3)
    - April 5: Our Quest for Faith: Is Humanism Enough? (Box 1-3)
    - April 12: A Margin Worth Fighting For (Box 1-3)
    - June 14: The Re-Education of Americans (Box 1-3)
    - November 8: The Israeli-Arab Conflict: The Human Conscience (Box 1-3)
  - 1971-72
    - April 11, 1971 Acts of War: The Guilt and The Responsibility, An Easter Address (Box 1-3)
    - May 14, 1972 War or Peace: The National Emergency -The New York Board of Leaders and the President of the Society (Box 1-3)
  - 1973-1980 - 2 Folders (Box 1-3)
  - 1981-1 Folder (Box 1-3)
- Series III: Radio Talks, 1934 -1953
  - 1934 (Box 4-5)
    - January: War Myths, 0ld and New (Box 4-5)
  - 1935
    - November 21: (discussion re: pros and cons of U.S. collective action with League of Nations.) (Box 4-5)
  - 1939
    - September 10: Doess Modern Man Need Religion? (Box 4-5)
  - 1940
    - April 2: The Census (Box 4-5)
    - April 9: The McLaughlin Bill (Box 4-5)
    - April 23: The Fifth Column (Box 4-5)
    - April 30: The Third Term (Box 4-5)
    - May 7: Wanted: A Plan (Box 4-5)
    - May 14: Realities -Needs --Social Behavior (Box 4-5)
    - May 21: America's Responsibility (Box 4-5)
    - May 28: Amer. Awakening Education (Box 4-5)
    - October 4: Election Issues (Box 4-5)
    - October 11: The Draft (Box 4-5)
    - October 18: Famine Relief (Box 4-5)
    - October 25: Civil Liberties (Box 4-5)
    - November 5: Election Night (Box 4-5)
    - November 12: Mr. Willkie and Mr. Roosevelt (Box 4-5)
    - November 19: Labor and Defense Contracts (sponsored by WQXR) (Box 4-5)
    - November 25: Being a Good Neighbor December (Box 4-5)
    - December 2: Nazi Propaganda (Box 4-5)
    - December 10: Propaganda (Box 4-5)
    - December 17: America’s Defense (Box 4-5)
    - December 24: A Christmas Present for Everyone (Box 4-5)
    - December 31: New Years Eve (Box 4-5)
  - 1941
    - January 7: The President's Address (Box 4-5)
    - January 21: American Youth Today (Box 4-5)
    - January 28: Child Labor (Box 4-5)
    - February 4: Group Responsibility and National Defense (Box 4-5)
    - February 11: Rapp-Coudert Committee (Box 4-5)
    - February 17: Integrity (Box 4-5)
    - February 25: The Faiths Men Hold (Box 4-5)
    - March 4: On Defeatism and Extremism (Box 4-5)
    - March 11: The Negro Question (Box 4-5)
    - March 18: On Fear (Box 4-5)
    - March 25: Civil Liberties (Box 4-5)
    - April 1: The Refugee Problem (Box 4-5)
    - April 8: Strikes and the Defense Program (Box 4-5)
    - April 22: The Doctors (Box 4-5)
    - April 29: Charles Lindbergh and America First (Box 4-5)
    - May 13: Isolation and America in Decision (Box 4-5)
    - May 20: The Awakening of American Citizenry (Box 4-5)
    - May 27: The President's Message (Box 4-5)
    - June 3: War and Peace Aims (Box 4-5)
    - June 10: The Transport Workers’ Union and the Subways (Box 4-5)
    - June 17: What the Nazi Consuls Leave (Box 4-5)
    - June 24: Real Democratic Defense (Box 4-5)
    - September 6: America's Role (Box 4-5)
    - September 13: Freedom of the Seas (Box 4-5)
    - September 20: Anti-Semitism and Mr. Lindbergh and Mr. Nye (Box 4-5)
    - September 27: Movies (Box 4-5)
    - October 4: Our Attitude Toward Russia (Box 4-5)